Guide to The Nation Records TAM.682
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Nation Records
1945-2003
1985-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Nation, The
Stack, Teresa
TAM.682
401.25 Linear Feet in 383 record cartons, 35 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize flat boxes, and 1 small media box
The Nation magazine, founded in 1865, is the oldest continuously circulating weekly in the United States. Featuring left-leaning articles on topics ranging from arts and culture to politics and world events, The Nation seeks to foster public discourse, instigate direct action, and incite debate, having published articles from prominent thought leaders. This collection consists of materials created and collected by the editorial and administrative staff of The Nation during the mid- and late-20th century documenting their daily activities, their editorial processes, and their administrative functions. Materials include books, pamphlets, correspondence, memoranda, financial records, article drafts, research notes for articles, newspaper clippings (both from The Nation and other publications), letters to the editor (both published and unpublished), and audio and video recordings in various formats (often of conferences or interviews). Prominent themes and historical events documented in the materials include Cold War foreign policy, the United Nations, and military spending operations, as well as arts and culture.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Teresa Stack on behalf of the Nation Company, LLC in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.072.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received by the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Nation magazine, founded in 1865, is the oldest continuously circulating weekly in the United States. Featuring left-leaning articles on topics ranging from arts and culture to politics and world events, The Nation seeks to foster public discourse, instigate direct action, and incite debate, having published articles from prominent thought leaders including Eleanor Roosevelt, Albert Einstein, Gore Vidal, Martin Luther King, Jr., and Christopher Hitchens. The magazine has also published investigative pieces about government spending and military activity. It was banned in several educational institutions during the Second Red Scare in the 1940s-50s, and has been involved in several high-profile lawsuits including a suit it brought against the United States Department of Defense in 1991 during the First Gulf War. As of 2016, its current editor and publisher is Katrina Vanden Heuvel.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by the editorial and administrative staff of The Nation during the mid- and late-20th century documenting their daily activities, their editorial processes, and their administrative functions. Materials include books, pamphlets, correspondence, memoranda, financial records, article drafts, research notes for articles, newspaper clippings (both from The Nation and other publications), letters to the editor (both published and unpublished), and audio and video recordings in various formats (often of conferences or interviews). Prominent themes and historical events documented in the materials include Cold War foreign policy, the United Nations, and military spending operations, as well as arts and culture. Editorial, correspondence, and subject files held by the magazine's editors, including Carey McWilliams, Hamilton Fish, Victor Navasky, and Katrina Vanden Heuevel are particularly well-represented.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Separated Materials
Approximately 55 linear feet of material were appraised, deaccessioned, and destroyed following accessioning, including books, back issues, newspaper clippings, and financial records. These materials were identified as being either duplicative, not archival in nature, damaged by mold, or beyond the scope of the research strength of the collection.
Appraisal
In January 2020, 3 record cartons of research files and rejection letters were appraised by a curator and deaccessioned due to lack of research value and preservation concerns.
United States -- Politics and government -- Periodicals.; Magazines (Periodicals); Nation (New York, N.Y.: 1865); Navasky, Victor S.; Stack, Teresa; Vanden Heuvel, Katrina; Blanshard, Paul, 1892-1980; Fish, Hamilton, 1951-; McWilliams, Carey, 1905-1980
- McWilliams (1/2), Undated (Box 1)
- Letters Victor Navasky A-Z, Editor File No 1, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
- McWilliams, Undated (Box 3)
- Editor Kai Bird Correspondence Files A-Z, 1978 (Box 4)
- Navasky Files, Undated (Box 5)
- McWilliams Contributor Contracts, Correspondence A-G, 1956-1973 (Box 6)
- Advertising (1/2), 2004 (Box 7)
- Letters to the Editor, 2000 (Box 8)
- James Storrow Files, 1968-1970 (Box 9)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence A-R, Puffin, Navasky vs. Randosh Debeate (2/2), 2005 (Box 10)
- "Files to be Archived" (2/2), 2013 (Box 11)
- Jack Berkowitz Files, 2001 Union Negotiations, TV Commercial Videos (2/2), 1995-1997, 2001 (Box 12)
- Victor Navasky A-W (2/2), 2004 (Box 13)
- Neil Black Files, 1st Half of Jack Berkowitz Files (2/2), 1995-1997 (Box 14)
- Victor Navasky A-H, 2004 (Box 15)
- Jack Berkowitz Files, 2001 Union Negotiations, TV Commercial Videos (1/2), 1995-1997, 2001 (Box 16)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Files (1), 1995-2004 (Box 17)
- Victor Navasky A-W (1/2), 2004 (Box 18)
- ND (1), Undated (Box 19)
- Neil Black Files, 1st Half of Jack Berkowitz Files (1/2), 1995-1997 (Box 20)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence A-R, Puffin, Navasky vs. Randosh Debeate (1/2), 2005 (Box 21)
- George Black Files (2), 1989-1991 (Box 22)
- McWilliams Contributor Contracts, Correspondence A-G (2/2), 1956-1973 (Box 23)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-Z (2/2), 2004 (Box 24)
- Archives Files from Katrina's Office (Speeches, Invitations, Articles, Rejected Mansucript Lists, Resumes, Transcripts of Meetings) (1/2), 1996-2006 (Box 25)
- 1996-1999, Undated (Box 26)
- McWilliams #10 Correspondence H-Z, Subject Clippings (1/2), 1954-1973 (Box 27)
- "Files to be Archived" (1/2), 2013 (Box 28)
- Navasky Correspondence Files, 1998 (Box 29)
- George Black Files A-C (1/2), 1989-1991 (Box 30)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel, Undated (Box 31)
- George Black Files A-C (2/2), 1989-1991 (Box 32)
- Victor Navasky Memos, Ad Budget, Associated Pub, Circ, Edit, Institute, Et al (2/2), Undated (Box 33)
- Victor Navasky Memos, Ad Budget, Associated Pub, Circ, Edit, Institute, Et al (2/2), Undated (Box 34)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence H-Z (1/2), 2005-2006 (Box 35)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence H-Z (2/2), 2005-2006 (Box 36)
- Last Half of Berkowitz, Move to 33 Irving, 2nd Half of Berkowitz (2/2), 1998 (Box 37)
- McWilliams Correspondence (2/2), 1955 (Box 38)
- McWilliams Correspondence (1/2), 1955 (Box 39)
- Last Half of Berkowitz, Move to 33 Irving, 2nd Half of Berkowitz (1/2), 1998 (Box 40)
- ACT 01102768 (1/2), Undated (Box 41)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-G, Boondocks, Danny Goldberg (1/2), 2001-2006 (Box 42)
- George Black Files (1/2), 1989-1991 (Box 43)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-Z (1/2), 2004 (Box 44)
- Victor Navasky A-H (1/2), 2004 (Box 45)
- A Matter of Opinion (1/2), 2005 (Box 46)
- Victor Navasky A-Be (2/2), Undated (Box 47)
- Victor Navasky Lawsuits #19 No. 1, Undated (Box 48)
- Penny Lernoux, Undated (Box 49)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (2/2), 1986 (Box 50)
- Original Disk Nation Co. LP and Nation Institute Inc (software and original disk), 1985-1997 (Box 51)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence A-Z (2/2), 1979-1981 (Box 52)
- Victor Navasky Clippings (2/2), 1969 (Box 53)
- McWilliams, Undated (Box 54)
- "Archives", 1982 (Box 55)
- McWilliams German Fact Finding Tour; Pershins NATO, 1982 (Box 56)
- Letters to the Editor (Unpublished), 1995 (Box 57)
- Letters to the Editor (Unpublished), 1996 (Box 58)
- James Storrow Files (1/2), 1970-1976 (Box 59)
- Carey McWilliams Editorial Files (1/2), 1933-1975 (Box 60)
- Iris and Carey McWilliams Files A-M, 1973 (Box 61)
- Joanne Inypijensk Correspondence, 1990 (Box 62)
- Victor Navasky subject Files, 1978-1982 (Box 63)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 64)
- Letters to the Editor (Unpublished), 1997 (Box 65)
- Editor Kai Bird Correspondence Files A-Z, Undated (Box 66)
- Victor Navasky A-Z file 12 (2/2), 1982 (Box 67)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence File #27 (2/2), 1987 (Box 68)
- Allan Nairn: Haiti Etc (2/2), Undated (Box 69)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence File #27 (1/2), 1987 (Box 70)
- McWilliams Files (2/2), Undated (Box 71)
- Victor Navasky J-Z (2/2), 2000-2003 (Box 72)
- Victor Navasky C-H (1/2), 2000-2003 (Box 73)
- Victor Navasky A-Be (1/2), Undated (Box 74)
- Victor Navasky T-Z; Nation Utah (1/2), Undated (Box 75)
- Victor Navasky: A/B Office Mise (1/2), 2000-2003 (Box 76)
- Victor Navasky A-Z File #12 (1/2), 1984 (Box 77)
- Victor Navasky A-Z; Editor File 1, 1978-1979 (Box 78)
- Victor Navasky/ND B-C (1/2), Undated (Box 79)
- Carey McWilliams Correspondence Files and Clippings (2/2), 1956-1975 (Box 80)
- Nation: #1 Ford Memoirs (2/2), 1984 (Box 81)
- "Archival Materials" (1/2), Undated (Box 82)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-Z (1/2), 1994 (Box 83, Box 425, Box 426, Box 427)
- Allan Nairn: Haiti Etc (1/2), Undated (Box 84)
- Editorial Correspondence and Miscellaneous Subject Folders (1/2), 1984-1998 (Box 85)
- Circulation, Fine Print, Print Orders, Fryiship Bills, Eastern/Kable, 3541s, 1997 (Box 86)
- GB Editorial Subject Files, 1989 (Box 87)
- "Archival Materials" (2/2), Undated (Box 88)
- Circulation Files (2/2), 1981-1982 (Box 89)
- Circulation Files (1/2), 1981-1982 (Box 90)
- "Archival Materials" (1/2), Undated (Box 91)
- Past CPJ Events and Projects; Abortion Statement; FBI Model Law (2/2), Undated (Box 92)
- Editorial/Literary Department (1/2), 1989-1995 (Box 93)
- Neil Black Files; David Parker (1/2), 1985-1990 (Box 94)
- David Parker Files; Neil Black (1/2), 1985-1990 (Box 95)
- Kopkind/Ethridge; Weekly Record, 1983 (Box 96)
- David Parker Files; Neil Black (2/2), 1985-1990 (Box 97)
- GB/Editorial Subject Files (2/2), 1987 (Box 98)
- Neil Black Files; David Parker (2/2), 1985-1990 (Box 99)
- GB/Editorial Subject Files (2/2), 1989 (Box 100)
- File IV: Past CPJ Events and Projects; Symposium on Presidential Power; Projects Unrealized (1/2), Undated (Box 101)
- Literary Department, 1989-1995 (Box 102)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1985 (Box 103)
- GB/Editorial Subject Files (1/2), 1987 (Box 104)
- Circulation; FCA Files, 1983-1984 (Box 105)
- Navasky Files, 1996-1999 (Box 106)
- Victor Navasky C-H (2/2), 2000-2003 (Box 107)
- Editorial Weekly Magazine Records (1/2), 1987-1988 (Box 108)
- Weekly Magazine Records (2/2), 1990-1991 (Box 109)
- Past Events and Projects; Tapes of Meetings and Conferences (1/2), Undated (Box 110)
- Weekly Magazine Records (1/2), 1990-1991 (Box 111)
- Taxes (1/2), 1986 (Box 112)
- Editorial MS (1/2), 1987 (Box 113)
- COS; Bank Reconciliation; Interstate; Boatmans (2/2), 1990-1994 (Box 114)
- Weekly Magazine Records (2/2), 1983-1984 (Box 115)
- MS/Editorial Files A-O (2/2), 1988 (Box 116)
- Kutt A-Z Correspondence (2/2), 1999 (Box 117)
- Victor Navasky A-Z; Kai Bird File #2 (2/2), 1979 (Box 118)
- FOIA, Undated (Box 119)
- Past CPJ Events and Projects; Abortion Statement; FBI Model Law (2/2), Undated (Box 120)
- Taxes (2/2), 1986 (Box 121)
- Victor Navasky A-Z; Kai Bird File #2 (1/2), 1979 (Box 122)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (1/2), 1985 (Box 123)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence (2/2), 1994 (Box 124)
- "Archival Materials" McWilliams Awards, Undated (Box 125)
- Kutt A-Z Correspondence (1/2), 1999 (Box 126)
- Weekly Magazine Record (1/2), 1983-1984 (Box 127)
- MS/Editorial Files A-O (1/2), 1988 (Box 128)
- Past Events and Projects; Tapes of Meetings and Conferences (1/2), Undated (Box 129)
- Intern Files (2/2), 1992-1996 (Box 130)
- Intern Files (1/2), 1992-1996 (Box 131)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1986 (Box 132)
- Allan Nairn #2: IND/GNATIES (2/2), Undated (Box 133)
- Victor Navasky: Personal Files A-R (2/2), 1983 (Box 134)
- SCN Rosenbergs; Hiss (1/2), Undated (Box 135)
- James Storrow Files (2/2), 1970-1976 (Box 136)
- Nation Institute; FBI Files; Rosenberg Debate (3/3), Undated (Box 137)
- Hamilton Fish Correspondence (2/2), 1983-1987 (Box 139)
- SCN Rosenbergs; Hiss (2/2), Undated (Box 140)
- Lawsuits (2/2), Undated (Box 141)
- Nation Libel Materials; Victor Navasky Media and Demo; Brazil; Swarthmore (1/2), 1995 (Box 142)
- Joan Wypijewski (1/2), Undated (Box 143)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence S-Z, 1996-1997 (Box 144)
- Joan Wypijewski (1/2), Undated (Box 145)
- Joan Wypijewski (2/2), Undated (Box 146)
- Navasky PEN Files, 1991-1992 (Box 147)
- Joan Wypijewski (1/2), Undated (Box 148)
- Allan Nairn #5: Ire/Great/ES/Haiti (1/2), Undated (Box 149)
- Original Letters MSS, 1996-1997 (Box 150)
- L-Z, 2004 (Box 151)
- Nation Institute FBI Files; Rosenberg Debate (1/3), Undated (Box 152)
- Hamilton Fish Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 153)
- Victor Navasky Personal File A-R (1/2), 1983 (Box 154)
- Victor Navasky Notes and Reviews; Safire Articles #4 (2/2), Undated (Box 155)
- Victor Navasky General Correspondence (2/2), 1982 (Box 156)
- Nation Institute; Kal-007; Prejury; Misc. (2/2), 1979-1984 (Box 157)
- Victor Navasky Notes and Reviews; Safire Articles #4 (1/2), Undated (Box 158)
- Victor Navasky General Correspondence (1/2), 1982 (Box 159)
- Nation (Libel Materials); Victor Navasky and Dem; Brazil; Swarthmore (2/2), 1995 (Box 160)
- Nation Institute; Kal-007; Prejury; Misc. (1/2), 1979-1984 (Box 161)
- Lawsuits (1/2), Undated (Box 162)
- Victor Navasky: Opinions on Supreme; Correspondence; New Stateman; Khrushkev; Saving the Nation, 1993-2007 (Box 163)
- Joan Wypijewski (2/2), Undated (Box 164)
- CDS: Bank Reconciliation; Interstate; Boatmans (1/2), 1990-1995 (Box 165)
- CPJ Files (2/2), Undated (Box 166)
- Kai Bird Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 167)
- Earned Income Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 168)
- Billing Reports, 1990 (Box 169)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (1/2), Undated (Box 170)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (2/2); Foriner Interns (1/2), 1976-1980, 1997-2001 (Box 171)
- Foriner Interns (2/2), 1997-2001 (Box 172)
- Victor Navasky Letters, Undated (Box 173)
- Kutt Correspondence A-G; Victor Navasky MSS Submissions (1/2), 1978-1981, 2001-2002 (Box 174)
- Victor Navasky MSS Submissions (2/2), 1978-1981 (Box 175)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1981 (Box 176)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1981 (Box 177)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1980 (Box 178)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence T-Z, 1981 (Box 179)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 180)
- Committee for Public Justice (1/2), 1970-1983 (Box 181)
- Committee for Public Justice (2/2), 1970-1983 (Box 182)
- Allan Nairn: Ind/GNAT/ES/HART (1/2), Undated (Box 183)
- Allan Nairn: Ind/GNAT/ES/HART (2/2), Undated (Box 184)
- Allan Nairn (1/2), Undated (Box 185)
- Joan Wypijewski Miscellaneous Files (1/2), 1980s-early 1990s (Box 186)
- Allan Nairn (2/2), Undated (Box 187)
- Joan Wypijewski Miscellaneous Files (2/2), 1980s-early 1990s (Box 188)
- Victor Navasky (1/2), Undated (Box 189)
- Nation Institute: Boston Roundtable (2/2), 1984-1985 (Box 190)
- Original Letters MSS, 1996-1997 (Box 191)
- L-Z (2/2), 2004 (Box 192)
- Unpublished Letters (2/2), 2007-2008 (Box 193)
- Letters to the Editor (2/2), 1981-1986 (Box 194)
- Victor Navasky MSS; Correspondence (2/2), 1984-1985 (Box 195)
- Letters to the Editor (1/2), 1981-1986 (Box 196)
- Nation Institute: Boston Roundtable (1/2), 1984-1985 (Box 197)
- Victor Navasky Clippings File #6; O-Z (1/2), Undated (Box 198)
- Nation Institute KAL 007; Prejury Miscellaneous (3/3), 1979-1984 (Box 199)
- Nation Institute: Boston Roundtable Readers and Tapes #2; Alger Hiss Books #2 (1/2), Undated (Box 200)
- Victor Navasky MSS; Correspondence (1/2), 1984-1985 (Box 201)
- Playlist Records and Original MSS for Letters, By Issue (1/2), 1994-1995 (Box 202)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence, NCE; A-I (2/2), 1996 (Box 203)
- Nation Classified Files (2/2), 1988-1990 (Box 204)
- Playlist Records and Original MSS for Letters, By Issue (2/2), 1994-1995 (Box 205)
- Victor Navasky Clippings (1/2), 1960 (Box 206)
- Nation Classified Files (1/2), 1988-1990 (Box 207)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-I (1/2), 1996 (Box 208)
- Victor Navasky Subject File #7 (1/2), 1984 (Box 209)
- Victor Navasky Subject File #7 (2/2), 1984 (Box 210)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence J-S (2/2), 1994 (Box 211)
- Writer's Congress/Videotapes (2/2), Undated (Box 212)
- Joan Wypijewski (1/2), Undated (Box 213)
- Victor Navasky Ke-Me (1/2); Allan Nairn #3 Ind/Guat/ES (1/2), Undated (Box 214)
- Joan Wypijewski (2/2); Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence J-S (1/2), Undated (Box 215)
- Victor Navasky "Hold Files" (1/2), 1987-1991 (Box 216)
- Intern Files (2/2), 1981-1991 (Box 217)
- Victor Navasky I-S (2/2), 2000-2003 (Box 218)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence (1/2), 2000 (Box 219)
- File II Past CPJ Events and Projects; FBI Model: Privacy Meeting (1/2), Undated (Box 220)
- Intern Files (1/2), 1982-1991 (Box 221)
- File II Past CPJ Events and Projects; FBI Model: Privacy Meeting (2/2), Undated (Box 222)
- Editorial and Business Files (1/2), 1966-1968 (Box 223)
- Victor Navasky I-S (2/2), 2000-2003 (Box 224)
- Victor Navasky J-Z (1/2), 2000-2003 (Box 225)
- Nation: #1 Ford Memoirs (1/2), 1984 (Box 226)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence (2/2), 2000 (Box 227)
- Editorial and Business Files (2/2), 1966-1968 (Box 228)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence A-F (2/2), 1995 (Box 229)
- Allan Nairn #5: Ire/Guat/ES/Haiti (2/2); Victor Navasky Experts Speak, Undated (Box 230)
- KVH Correspondence- Contributors, 2000-2008 (Box 231)
- KVH Correspondence/Subject Files, 2000-2008 (Box 232)
- Navasky Correspondence A-D, 1979-1981 (Box 233)
- Navasky Correspondence P-S, 1979-1981 (Box 234)
- Navasky Correspondence M-0/ Nation Cruise Surveys, 1979-1981, 2002-2005 (Box 235)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence I-S/ Nation Cruise Surveys, 2002-2005 (Box 236)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence (1/2), 2003 (Box 237)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence (2/2); Katrina Vanden Huevel Personal (1/2), 2003, 2010 (Box 238)
- Katrina Vanden Huevel Personal (2/2), 2010 (Box 239)
- CPJ Files (1/2), Undated (Box 240)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence A-F (1/2), 1995 (Box 241)
- McWilliams Files; WH Surveillance (1/2), 1952 (Box 242)
- Carey McWilliams Correspondence Files and Clippings (1/2), 1956-1965 (Box 243)
- McWilliams Files; WH Surveillance (2/2), 1952 (Box 244)
- Navasky "Hold Files" (2/2); Victor Navasiky Ke-Me (1/2), 1987-1991 (Box 245)
- Navasky Subject File, Correspondence, Notepads, 1978-1981, 1986, 2002-2003 (Box 246)
- Letters to the Editor, 2001 (Box 247)
- Unpublished letters to the editor, 2007-2008 (Box 248)
- Carey McWilliams Correspondence and Clippings (2/2), 1956-1965 (Box 249)
- Allan Nairn #3: Ind/Guat/ES (2/2), Undated (Box 250)
- Weekly Mag Records; Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence (1/2), 1989, 1994 (Box 251)
- Video/audiotapes from the Nation Institute (1/3), Undated (Box 252)
- Barton J-Misc (2/3), 2004 (Box 253)
- Barton J-Misc (3/3), 2004 (Box 254)
- Video/audiotapes from the Nation Institute (2/3), Undated (Box 255)
- Footnote on Alger Hiss Books, Undated (Box 256)
- Weekly Mag Records; Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence (2/2), 1989, 1994 (Box 257)
- Barton J-Misc (1/3), 2004 (Box 258)
- Honorary Degress/Certificates, Undated (Box 259)
- Original Disk; Nation Co. LP and Nation Institute Inc (2/2), 1985-1997 (Box 260)
- SCW Judicial Selection; Miscellaneous Archives (2/2), 1985-1988 (Box 261)
- James Storrow No. 2 Clippings #2, 1968-1970 (Box 262)
- Victor Navasky General and Specific Files #11 (2/2), 1980-1981 (Box 263)
- Victor Navasky D-F (2/2), Undated (Box 264)
- SCW Judicial Selection; Miscellaneous Archives (1/2), 1985-1988 (Box 265)
- Hamilton Fish (1/2), Undated (Box 266)
- Victor Navasky D-F (1/2), Undated (Box 267)
- Videotapes (2/2), Undated (Box 268)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (1/2), 1993 (Box 269)
- FOIA (Index in Front (2/2), Undated (Box 270)
- FOIA (Index in Front (1/2), Undated (Box 271)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence (2/2), 1997-1998 (Box 272)
- Katrina Vanden Heuevel Correspondence S-XYZ, 1997-1998 (Box 273)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence Chronological (2/2); Lasa, Undated (Box 274)
- Victor Navasky (2/2), 1996-1997 (Box 275)
- R. Lingeman Files: Personal, Editorial, Guide (1/2), Undated (Box 276)
- Assorted Author Correspondence, Back Issues, Fact-checking Files, 1992-1995 (Box 277)
- Katrina Vanden Huevel Correspondence I-Z (1/2), 2001 (Box 278)
- Katrina Vanden Huevel Correspondence A-H (1/2), 1997-1998 (Box 279)
- Victor Navasky Chronological Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 280)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence I-S (1/2), 1997 (Box 281)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence Chronological (1/2), 1989 (Box 282)
- Kutt Correspondence G-O (1/2), 1995 (Box 283)
- A-R and Office (1/2), 1999 (Box 284)
- Victor Navasky (1/2), 1996-1997 (Box 285)
- Katrina Vanden Heuvel Correspondence A-H (2/2), 1997-1998 (Box 286)
- A-R and Office (2/2), 1999 (Box 287)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (2/2), 1991 (Box 288)
- Victor Navasky A-K (2/2), 1996-1997 (Box 289)
- Unpublished Letters (1/2), 2005 (Box 290)
- Unpublished Letters to the Editor (1/2), 2008-2009 (Box 291)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (1/2), 1991 (Box 292)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence Alphabetical (1/2), 1990 (Box 293)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence Alphabetical (2/2), 1990 (Box 294)
- Kutt Correspondence G-O (2/2), 1995 (Box 295)
- Victor Navasky OPM L-Z (1/2), 1999 (Box 296)
- Victor Navasky A-K (2/2), 1996-1997 (Box 297)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (2/2), 1987 (Box 298)
- Letters to the Editor (1/2), 1999 (Box 299)
- Victor Navasky Correspodnence Alphabetical and Chronological (1/2), 1988 (Box 300)
- Victor Navasky Correspodnence Alphabetical and Chronological (2/2), 1988 (Box 301)
- Unpublished Letters (1/2), 2006 (Box 302)
- Victor Navasky Correspondence (1/2), 1987 (Box 303)
- Dialogo II 120th (2/2), Undated (Box 304)
- Nation Business Memos (In File) (1/2), Undated (Box 305)
- Dialogo (2/2), Undated (Box 306)
- Katrina Vanden Huevel Correspondence M-Z (2/2), 1994 (Box 307)
- Kutt Correspondence P-Z (2/2), 1995 (Box 308)
- Victor Navasky G-Ke (1/2), Undated (Box 309)
- Victor Navasky: Lawsuits File #19-No.2, Undated (Box 310)
- AFL-CIO Department of Community Service Files from Writer's Watch (1/2), 1985-1987 (Box 311)
- Victor Navasky G-Ke (2/2), Undated (Box 312)
- AFL-CIO Department of Community Service Files from Writer's Watch (1/2), 1985-1987 (Box 313)
- SCW Boris (2/2), 1982-1987 (Box 314)
- R. Lingeman Files: Personal, Editorial, Guide (1/2), Undated (Box 315)
- CDST Deposit Reports (2/2), 1990-1993 (Box 316)
- Journalism Prizes and Awards; Tables of Contents; Magazine; Nation Institute (1/2), 1980-1986 (Box 317)
- POT SCW Nominees; D. Ginsburg; E. Meese (2/2), 1985-1987 (Box 318)
- R. Lingeman Editorial Files; Dep VE (2/2), 1979-1995 (Box 319)
- Permissions (2/2), 1987-1991 (Box 320)
- R. Lingeman Editorial Files; Dep VE (1/2), 1979-1995 (Box 321)
- Permissions (1/2), 1987-1991 (Box 322)